

Mihir Pavuskar

A-403, Konkar's Nest, Near Agali Estate, Agali Margao, Goa 9420897121 pavuskarmihir@gmail.com <u>GitHub</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Personal Website</u>

ABOUT ME

Software Developer at Murf Al. Graduate from Vellore Institute of Technology with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and Engineering with hands-on experience gained student-centric, growth-oriented through internships. Interested in Software Development, Machine Learning, and Computer Vision and developing bleeding-edge technologies.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science and Engineering Vellore Institute of Technology Vellore, Tamil Nadu 05/2022 CGPA - 9.23

PROJECTS

SMART CHECKOUT SYSTEM

- A smart checkout system inspired by the Amazon Go store, coupled with inventory management and a sales prediction system.
- · LSTM, ReactJS, NodeJS, Docker

COVID VISUALIZER

- A COVID data visualization dashboard that presented the information in several different graphical formats gave us a deeper insight into the spread of the virus.
- · Pandas, Plotly, Plotly-Dash

SEE-FOOD

- Shazam for Food, can identify and classify up to 500 dishes using uploaded or live pictures
- · Tensorflow, TFJS, ReactJS, OpenCV

SQL to NOSQL DB CONVERTER

- A tool to migrate for SQL databases such as MySQL, MSSQL and PostgreSQL to NoSQL databases such as MongoDB
- MySQL, MSSQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, NodeJS

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer 09/2022 - present MURF AI - Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Visiting Researcher 02/2022 - 07/2022 Deakin University - Geelong, Australia

- Part of final year capstone internship.
- Working on an End-to-End Financial Document Question-Answering Model. Aiming for journal publication.

Full Stack Engineer 01/2022 - 04/2022 Velozity Global Solutions India Pvt. Ltd.

- Worked on both frontend and backend development of several projects.
- Collaborated with over 7 others while working on the projects.
- Worked with several technologies like ReactJS, NodeJS, NextJS, NestJS, ChakraUI, ReactStrap, etc.
- Developed ECG monitoring interface, Business landing websites and demonstration web apps.

Research Intern 07/2020 - 03/2021 Samsung PRISM - Vellore, Tamil Nadu

- Develop an Intelligent Text Normalization for ASR systems that would be used in SAMSUNG products in the future.
- Worked with advanced technologies such as BERT networks and XgBoost models.
- Were able to achieve 99.7% accuracy with the proposed model.

Lead React JS Developer 12/2019 - 05/2020 CamCann - Vellore, Tamil Nadu

- Developed projects such as Online Education Portal, Smart Advertisement System, and Smart Security Dashboard
- Led 4 interns

Lead Web Developer 10/2019 - 04/2020 Vorby - Vellore, Tamil Nadu

- · Developed Student Aid Portal
- · Led 2 Jr. Interns

CERTIFICATIONS

Deep Learning Specialization

Coursera - Andrew Ng

The Deep Learning Specialization is a foundational program that will help you understand the capabilities, challenges, and consequences of deep learning and prepare you to participate in the development of leading-edge AI technology.

Python Data Visualization

Coursera - Rice University

This specialization is intended for beginners who would like to master essential data visualization skills.

AWS - Cloud Practitioner

Amazon Web Services

This credential helps organizations identify and develop talent with critical knowledge related to implementing cloud initiatives. Earning AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner validates cloud fluency and foundational AWS knowledge.

Security Analyst (SSC/Q0901) **NASSCOM**

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

The Comedy Club, VIT **Co-Founder and Board Member**

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

Served as the Club Secretary and managed permissions as well as human resources. Organized multiple events both online and offline.

Red Cross, VIT **Club Member**

Jul 2019 - May 2020

Participated in multiple online and offline events organized to raise awareness on social issues.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- Deep Learning
- Data Science
- Computer Vision
- Big Data
- Databases
- Node.js

- Machine Learning
- Data Visualization
- Natural Language Processing
- · Data Structures and Algorithms
- ReactJS

CURRENT RESEARCH

Hand-gesture swipe keyboard text input system

Hand gesture-based text input systems are inefficient and difficult for humans to execute. They require a lot of time to input simple texts or may even need the user to learn certain sign languages to interact with the system. To address these issues, we propose a hand gesture-based swipe keyboard system. This paper implements the said methodology and compares it with the existing prevalent technique of text input.

INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

- Comedy Sketches
 Chess
- Stand-up Comedy Reading
- Table Tennies
- Video Games

LANGUAGES

- English 9/10
- Hindi 7/10
- Marathi 7/10
- Konkani 7/10
- French 5/10
- Kannada 3/10

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the information presented above is true to the best of my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars

Place: Margao

Mihir Mangesh Pavuskar